Guide to the Brooklyn Arts Council Folk Arts collection CBHM.0002
Center for Brooklyn History
- Series 13: Williamsburg Bridge 100th Anniversary
  The Williamsburg Bridge 100th Birthday Celebration was held on June 22, 2003 at the Continental Army Plaza Park in Williamsburg. The event celebrated the history, occupational labor, and communities that distinguish the culture of the Williamsburg Bridge. The event featured a fourteen foot tall birthday cake, a procession across the bridge, storytellers, tours, food representing Bridge communities, and Bridge-themed art shows held at local galleries. Music performances included Jewish Chassidic dance, Puerto Rican songs, Dominican merengue tipico, the Italian giglio brass band, and a grand finale song tribute to the bridge. Related events were held before and after the June 22, 2003 celebration.
  Program Files include contracts, financial records, and correspondence with Empire Events Group, vendors, elected officials, and participants. Commemorative items produced for the event include t-shirts, banners, flyers and posters. Also included are banners printed with photographs and text tracing the Bridge's history and items used by Kay Turner to research the history of the Bridge. Papers outlining operations, responsibilities, and schedules for the day of the celebration are also included.
  Audiovisual items include VHS tapes of BCAT (local television) broadcasts and bridge research, as well as radio spots, event recordings, and Bridge opening day recordings on CD. Cassette tapes include interviews with participants, community members, and individuals involved with the Bridge. Photographs and slides include "Junior" Tirado making a cake for the celebration at 4Gs Trucking, performers, and photos of the Williamsburg Bridge. Photographs are print and digital.
  Items in boxes 99-101 labeled "Special Collections" are materials concerning the history of Williamsburg, the bulk of which are local newspapers and magazines dating 2000-2006. Also included are two folders with photographs and personal items from Williamsburg residents.
  - Sub-series 13.1: Program Files
    - Correspondence, Empire Events Group, 2003 (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, Email, Karen Rosenberg, Empire Events Group, 2003 (Box 85, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, General, 2002-2003 (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, Invitation to Participate to Vendors, 2003 (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, Invitations, Elected Officials, 2003 (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, Invitations, VIP, 2003 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, Promotional, 2003 (Box 85, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, Sample Letters, 2003 (Box 85, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, Thank You Letters, 2003 (Box 85, Folder 9)
    - Mailing List, 2003 (Box 85, Folder 10)
    - Meeting Sign-In Sheets, 2002 (Box 85, Folder 11)
    - Programming, Activities, 2003 (Box 85, Folder 12)
    - Programming, Banners, 2003 (Box 90, Item 1-7)
    - Programming, Banner Documents, 2003 (Box 85, Folder 13)
    - Programming, Booth Registration Packet, 2003 (Box 85, Folder 14)
    - Programming, Booth Registration, 2003 (Box 85, Folder 15)
    - Programming, Cake, 2003 (Box 85, Folder 16)
    - Programming, Daily Schedule, 2003 (Box 85, Folder 17)
    - Programming, Event Production, 2003 (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Programming, Event Signage, 2003 (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Programming, Hat Design, 2003 (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - Programming, ID Badges and Passes, 2003 (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Programming, Logo, 2003 (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Programming, Maps, 2003 (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Programming, Mayor's Office, 2003 (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - Programming, Movies, 2003 (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - Programming, Notes, 2003 (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - Programming, Participants, 2003 (Box 86, Folder 8)
    - Programming, Postcard and Pre-Events, 2003 (Box 86, Folder 9)
    - Programming, Posters, 2003 (Box 86, Folder 10)
    - Programming, Posters, Oversize (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - Programming, Program, 2003 (Box 86, Folder 11)
    - Programming, In Case of Rain, 2003 (Box 86, Folder 12)
    - Programming, Remarks by Participants, 2003 (Box 86, Folder 13)
    - Programming, Restaurants, 2003 (Box 86, Folder 14)
    - Programming, Souvenir Pins, 2003 (Box 90, Item 1-3)
    - Programming, Souvenir Water Bottles, 2003 (Box 90, Item 1-3)
    - Programming, Tee Shirt Design, 2003 (Box 86, Folder 15)
    - Programming, Tee Shirts, 2003 (Box 90)
    - Programming, Vendors, Business Cards and Flyers, 2003 (Box 86, Folder 16)
    - Programming, Vehicle Permit, 2003 (Box 86, Folder 17)
    - Programming, Vendor List, 2003 (Box 86, Folder 18)
    - Programming, VIP, 2003 (Box 86, Folder 19)
    - Contracts, City Services, Contracts and Permits, 2003 (Box 86, Folder 20)
    - Contracts, Empire Events Group, 2003 (Box 86, Folder 21)
    - Contracts, Letters of Agreement (empty), 2003 (Box 86, Folder 22)
    - Financial, Budget, 2003 (Box 87, Folder 1-2)
    - Financial, Fundraising, General, 2003 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - Financial, Fundraising, Fleet, 2003 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Financial, Fundraising, Mark Monteverdi, ATT, 2003 (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Financial, Fundraising, NY Building Congress, 2003 (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Financial, Insurance, 2003 (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - Financial, POs and Invoice, 2003 (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - Publicity, BAC Newsletter, 2003 (Box 87, Folder 9)
    - Publicity, Daily News, 2003 (Box 87, Folder 10)
    - Publicity, New York Magazine, 2003 (Box 87, Folder 11)
    - Publicity, Time Out New York, 2003 (Box 87, Folder 12)
    - Publicity, NYFS Voices, 2003 (Box 87, Folder 13)
    - Publicity, Flyers and Clippings, 2003 (Box 87, Folder 14)
    - Publicity, Flyers, Spanish, 2003 (Box 87, Folder 15)
    - Publicity, Information Card, 2003 (Box 87, Folder 16)
    - Publicity, Placements, 2003 (Box 87, Folder 17)
    - Publicity, Postcard with Map, 2003 (Box 87, Folder 18)
    - Publicity, Press Book, 2003 (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Publicity, Press Conference, 2003 (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Publicity, Press Clippings, 2003 (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - Publicity, Press Kit, 2003 (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Publicity, Press Releases, 2003 (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - Related Events, Brooklyn Bridge Birthday Party, Contractors Breakfast, 2003 (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - Related Events, Historians Panel, NYHS, 2003 (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - Related Events, The Giglio and the Bridge, 2003 (Box 88, Folder 8)
    - Related Events, Williamsburg Bridge Centennial Breakfast, 2003 (Box 88, Folder 9)
    - Related Events, Opening Reception, 2003 (Box 88, Folder 10)
    - Dan Dalrymple, Postcards and Illustrations, 2003 (Box 88, Folder 11)
    - Jerry Dantzic, Photographer, 2003 (Box 90, Folder 6)
    - Larry Racioppo, O Giglio E Paradiso, 2003 (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - Work Files, Business Cards, 2003 (Box 88, Folder 12)
    - Work Files, "Current", 2003 (Box 88, Folder 13)
    - Work Files, Notebooks, 2003 (Box 88, Folder 14)
    - Work Files, "To Do", 2003 (Box 88, Folder 15)
    - Work Files, Williamsburg, Manhattan, 2003 (Box 88, Folder 16)
    - Bridge History, Artist and Community Interviews, 2003 (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Bridge History, 2003 (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Bridge History, Harper's Weekly, 1900 (Box 90, Folder 5)
    - Bridge History, Opening Program Photocopy, Short Story, 1903-1907 (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - Bridge History, Photographs, 2003 (Box 89, Folder 4)
    - Bridge History, Reconstruction DOT Brochures, 1999 (Box 89, Folder 5)
    - Bridge History, Reconstruction, DOT Brochures, 2000-2002 (Box 89, Folder 6)
    - Bridge History, Brooklyn Bridge, 2000-2002 (Box 89, Folder 7)
    - Oversize Posters, 2003 (Box 97, Folder 1)
    - Special Collections, Brooklyn Historical Society, 2000 (Box 99, Folder 1)
    - Special Collections, Kitty Katz "Welcome to Williamsburg", 2003 (Box 99, Folder 2)
    - Special Collections, Angelo Cruz, 1945, 1970, 2003 (Box 99, Folder 3)
    - Special Collections, Alice Yuskowski Clauss, 1929-1947, 1968, 2000-2003 (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - Special Collections, CAF, 2003 (Box 99, Folder 5)
    - Special Collections, Diner, circa 2000 (Box 99, Folder 6)
    - Special Collections, Our Lady of Mt. Carmel Giglio, 2003-2004 (Box 99, Folder 7)
    - Special Collections, People's Firehouse, circa 2000 (Box 99, Folder 8)
    - Special Collections, Power Plant, 2002 (Box 99, Folder 9)
    - Special Collections, Safe-T Gallery, 2003-2005 (Box 99, Folder 10)
    - Special Collections, Unseen 2 Urban Navigator, circa 2000 (Box 99, Folder 11)
    - Special Collections, 1211, 2001-2003 (Box 99, Folder 12)
    - Special Collections, 1211, 2003-2005 (Box 99, Folder 13)
    - Special Collections, BAC News, 2002 (Box 99, Folder 14)
    - Special Collections, Crain's NY Business, 2005 (Box 99, Folder 15)
    - Special Collections, NYC College of Technology Connections, 2004 (Box 99, Folder 16)
    - Special Collections, New York Magazine, 2000-2003 (Box 99, Folder 17)
    - Special Collections, Time Out New York, 2000 (Box 99, Folder 18)
    - Special Collections, WAGMAG, 2003-2004 (Box 99, Folder 19)
    - Special Collections, Waterfront Week, 1996, 1999 (Box 99, Folder 20)
    - Special Collections, Block Magazine, 2002-2006 (Box 100, Folder 1-3)
    - Special Collections, The Brooklyn Rail, 2004-2005 (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - Special Collections, Greenpoint Star, 2003-2004 (Box 101, Folder 2)
    - Special Collections, New York Daily News, 1985 (Box 101, Folder 3)
    - Special Collections, Greenline, 2003 (Box 101, Folder 4)
    - Special Collections, Raw, 2007 (Box 101, Folder 5)
    - Special Collections, Roger Haight "Marcy Avenue", 1999 (Box 101, Folder 6)
  - Sub-series 13.2: Audiovisual
    Lina Manino, Aido's Restaurant, 5/26/2002
    Inez Pasher, WABA, 5/15/2003
    Mike Devine, Dime Savings Bank, 5/30/2003
    Sam Schwartz, Chief Engineer, 5/28/2003
    Maestro Belisano, undated
    José Matías, undated
    Natalio "Junior" Tirado Ruiz, undated
    John Meroda, Yonkers Construction, 5/9/2003
    Rabbi Weber, 5/25/2003
    Hernández Family, undated
    James Connor, undated
    Daniel Vederlinic, undated
    Elliot Gabey, 5/23
    Rabbi Nierderman, undated
    Neil Zenlenitz, undated
    Bobby Taylor, 5/23/2003
    Frank Kodah, DOT Williamsburg Bridge Restoration, undated
    Verghese Menachery, undated
    Jamey Barbas, Parsons, undated
    Connie Crawford, MTA, undated
    Anthony Grasso, WB, undated
    Kay Turner, undated
    Nelson Gonzalez, undated
    Marvin Gelfand, undated
    - Slides and Photographs, 2003 (Box 91)
    - Photographs, Slides, Discs, 2003 (Box 92)
    - BCAT Presents Williamsburg Bridge 100th Celebrations, VHS, 2003 (Box 93, Item 1-8)
    - Research, VHS, 1988, 2000 (Box 94, Item 1-8)
    - "Bridge" by Emma Hogarth, VHS, 2002-2003 (Box 94, Item 9-10)
    - Event Recordings and Images, CD, 2003 (Box 95, Item 1-5)
    - Event Radio Promotion, CD, 2003 (Box 95, Item 6-10)
    - Williamsburg Bridge Opening Day, CD, 2003 (Box 95, Item 11-12)
      Original recording dated December 19, 1903.
    - Music Inspired by the Williamsburg Bridge, CD, 2003 (Box 95, Item 13-14)
    - Recordings by Participating and Potential Artists, CD, circa 2000-2003 (Box 95, Item 15-18)
    - Interviews, Cassettes, 2003 (Box 96, Item 1-32)
    - Los Sures, Williamsburg Stories, 2003 (Box 96, Item 33-34)
    - Storytelling, DAT Cassettes, 2003 (Box 96, Item 35-39)
- Series 14: Brooklyn Arts Council Materials
  The materials in this series were created by the Brooklyn Arts Council, not for the Folk Arts program. Items in the Program Files sub-series include copies of BAC News, brochures for various events including film festivals, and brochures providing general information about the Brooklyn Arts Council. The Audiovisual sub-series includes copies of films screened at Scene: Brooklyn and Women of African Descent Film Festivals as well as a Brooklyn Arts Council event held at City Lore.
  - Sub-series 14.1: Program Files
    - BAC News, 1999-2005 (Box 98, Folder 6)
    - BAC News, Oversize, 2008 (Box 97, Folder 8)
    - BAC Brochures, Events, 2005-2007 (Box 98, Folder 7)
    - BAC Brochures, Film Festivals, 2002-2010 (Box 98, Folder 8)
    - BAC Brochures, General, circa 2005 (Box 98, Folder 9)
  - Sub-series 14.2: Audiovisual
    - BAC at City Lore, Video, 2014 (Box 98, Folder 10)
    - Scene: Brooklyn, 2008-2010 (Box 106, Item 1-35)
    - Women of African Descent Film Festival, 2009-2010 (Box 107, Item 1-25)